Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Audio-Visual Material, 7
  - Photographic prints and negatives, 2
    - Paul MacCready in Germany, 1999; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_13; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 13)
    - Paul MacCready at Hong Kong City Hall (HKUST), 1999 May; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_14; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 14)
      Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Lecture
    - American Academy of Achievement/National Air & Space Museum/MacCready residence, 1999 June; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_15; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 15)
    - Quetzacoatlus Northropi, 1999 June 15; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_16; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 16)
    - Bungee leg tests/Friends, 1999 July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_17; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 17)
    - AeroVironment shareholders meeting/Scuba trip/DARPA - NASA models, 1999 July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_18; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 18)
    - Paul MacCready and family/mini-plane models, 1999 August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_19; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 19)
    - Plane Models/Taras Kiceniuk, 1999 September; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_20; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 20)
    - Paul MacCready and T-28, 1999 October; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_21; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 21)
    - Santa Fe vacation photos, 1999 October - November; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_22; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 22)
    - Trial for Dempsey - MacCready prize, 1999 Fall - Winter; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_01; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 1)
    - Alan Alda and Scientific American, "Flying Free"/Bike Tests (1 of 2), 1999 December - 2000 January; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_02; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 2)
    - Alan Alda and Scientific American, "Flying Free" (2 of 2), 1999 December - 2000 January; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_03; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 3)
    - Gossamer Condor at the National Air & Space Museum, 2000 February; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_04; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 4)
    - Exoskeletons for Human Performance Augmentation - DARPA conference, 2000 March; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_05; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 5)
    - Black Sheep Squadron model airplane club/Soaring Convention in Albuquerque, NM, 2000 March; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_06; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 6)
    - Harvey Mudd Clinic/Black Sheep Squadron model airplane club, 2000 March-May; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_07; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 7)
    - Gossamer Albatross at the Museum of Flight/Lindbergh Foundation/Party for Barclay Lamb, ca. 2000 May; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_08; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 8)
    - Gossamer Albatross and Batso at the Museum of Flight/Workshop, 2000 May - July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_09; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 9)
    - Black Sheep Squadron model airplane club/ Workshop at MacCready home/Vacation photos, 2000 July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_10; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 10)
    - Gary Fogel - Book signing: "Wind and Wings: The History of Flight in San Diego"/Hell Creek, Montana, 2000 July - August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_11; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 11)
    - Gossamer Condor at National Air and Space Museum/Paul MacCready, et al., 2000 September - October; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_12; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 12)
    - Cooper Hewitt National Design Awards/Tyler MacCready, et al./MicroBat, 2000 November; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_13; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 13)
    - Plane models - Housefly, MicroBat/MacCready family members, et al., 2000 December; MacCreadyPB_07_02_011_14; Color photographs (Box 7.11, Folder 14)
    - Helios in Hawaii, 2001; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_01; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 1)
    - Santa Monica Museum of Flying, ca. 2001; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_02; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 2)
    - Paul MacCready and Alec Brooks at Caltech with PosiCharge/Impact, ca. 2001 - 2002; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_03; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 3)
    - Dick and Pip Smith/Model planes, 2001 January - February; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_04; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 4)
    - Judy and Tyler MacCready, 2001 July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_05; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 5)
    - Model airplane workshop, 2001 or 2002 July; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_06; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 6)
    - Tehachapi/Model planes, 2001 September; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_07; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 7)
    - Paul MacCready and pool vortex experiments, 2001 September 23; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_08; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 8)
    - Hang gliding/Model planes/Judy MacCready, ca. 2002; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_09; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 9)
    - Chrysler Design Awards/Trip to Texas/Miscellaneous, 2002; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_10; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 10)
    - Tyler MacCready, et al., 2002 August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_11; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 11)
    - Flying Convention, 2003; MacCreadyPB_07_02_012_12; Color photographs (Box 7.12, Folder 12)
    - Mounted photos of Gossamer Albatross, 1979
    - Gossamer Albatross, 1979; MacCreadyPB_07_02_013_01; Color photographs (Box 7.13, Folder 1)
  - Videos and Audio, 3
    - VHS Tapes Miscellaneous
    - 3-2-1 Contact: Bionic Bat winning 4th Kremer Prize Flight, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_01; VHS. Color. 9 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 1)
    - It will Never Work - Series Three, Programme 5, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_02; VHS. Color. 4 min. 52 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 2)
      Includes interview with MacCready about Pathfinder.
    - GM Sunraycer (Solar-powered car), undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_03; VHS. Color. 8 min. 50 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 3)
      Created by Bruce McCristal of General Motors.
    - Search for Adventure: Solar Challenger, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_04; VHS. Color. 46 min. 19 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 4)
      Created by Burrud, Cousteau, Horton, Inc. Written by Theodore Strauss, Produced and directed by Joseph Thompson. Series produced by Thomas Horton. Follows the creation and testing of the Gossamer Penguin and Solar Challenger.
    - Albatross: Dynamic Soaring, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_05; VHS. Color. 15 min. (Box 7.14, Folder 5)
      Created by by Gottfried Sachs, Holger Möller, Alexander Knoll, Rainer Mehlhorn Institute of Flight Mechanics and Flight Control. Computer simulated example of dynamic soaring.
    - Search for Adventure: Gossamer Albatross, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_06; VHS. Color. 53 min. (Box 7.14, Folder 6)
      Directed by Joseph Thompson. Produced by Thomas F. Horton, Joseph Thompson.
    - Parker MacCready Hydrofoil footage from Discover Magazine, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_07; VHS. Color. 4 min. 38 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 7)
      Discover Magazine. Clip of kayak, hydrofoil contest featuring Parker MacCready.
    - Newton's Apple, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_08; VHS. Color. 27 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 8)
      Segment on QN. Newton's Apple is a local public television show.
    - Real TV Gossamer Penguin breaks, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_09; VHS. Color. 31 min. 10 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 9)
      Footage is from Search for Adventure: Solar Challenger
    - TRW presentation. Artificial and Natural Flight, undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_10; VHS. Color. 50 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 10)
      Lecture given to TRW.
    - Miscellaneous Science (Tyler MacCready Walkalong, Fly Bower, Flapping, QN, Pogo, Van Sant), undated; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_11; VHS. Color. 13 min. 20 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 11)
      Various clips including one from AeroVironment, Japanese tv show, German student's CG albatross, pogo, Van Sant Flight Forms.
    - Flight Into Fantasy: The Achievement of Man-Powered Flight, ca. 1977; MacCreadyPB_07_03_014_12; VHS. Color. 22 min. 56 sec. (Box 7.14, Folder 12)
      Film of the Gossamer Condor by Jack Hobart
    - The Flight of the Gossamer Condor, 1978; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_01; VHS. Color. 27 min. (Box 7.15, Folder 1)
      Churchill Films presents a Shedd Production. Writer/Director/Editor: Ben Shedd. Producer: Jacqueline Phillips Shedd. Academy Award 1978 Best Documentary Short Subject
    - Sample DVD version of the Flight of the Condor film and Smithsonian National Air & Space Museum "Gossamer Condor Video Kiosk", 1978; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_02; DVD. Color. 35 min. (Box 7.15, Folder 2)
      Smithsonian. "Flight of the Gossamer Condor" is made by Churchill Films. 1978 Shedd Productions. Directed by Ben Shedd. Produced by Jacqueline Phillips Shedd
    - Mercantile Bank Gossamer Albatross commercial, 1979 August 30; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_03; VHS. Color. 30 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 3)
      Created by: MCI Productions, Dallas. 30 second ad for Mercantile Bank featuring Paul MacCready and Bryan Allen.
    - Spirales/ Flight Forms, 1985; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_04; VHS. Color. 20 min. (Box 7.15, Folder 4)
      Created by Andre Merle and Pierre Jallaud. Film of the 1956 World Soaring Championship in France, which MacCready won. French narration (no subtitles). This copy made in 1985.
    - Various clips 1. QN, Parker, models, 2. Solar flight & Bionic Bat, ca. 1985; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_05; VHS. Color. 29 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 5)
      Recorded programs taped off of TV. Interview with Parker MacCready on QN. Clip of Clio awards on PM Magazine (commercial advertisting), Interview of PBM ~14:00 with overview of GC, GA, Bionic Bat. Other programs and commercials not related to MacCready are also on the tape.
    - 1986 OM World Finals, MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_06; VHS. Color. 51 min. 10 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 6)
      Producer, Director and Editor: Ned Eckhardt, Carole and Sam Micklus. Overview of student competition held at Northern AZ University at Flagstaff. Interviews with coaches and participants.
    - Paul MacCready Speaking Engagements: Artificial and Natural Flights, Unusual Aircraft, 1986; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_07; VHS. Color. 2 hours (Box 7.15, Folder 7)
      Two different lectures: Savannah River and TRW
    - Unusual Aircraft, 1986 October 29; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_08; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 5 min. (Box 7.15, Folder 8)
      Lecture by Paul MacCready
    - Racing with the Sun, ca. 1987; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_09; VHS. Color. 38 min. 21 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 9)
      Created by: Dustlight Productions for National Geographic. Written by Jeanne Rawlings and William Livingston. Produced and Directed by William Livingston. First solar energy car race in Australia (3000km).
    - Ancient Wings #6, QN, OTW, Sam Johnson, 1987; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_10; VHS. Color. 46 min. (Box 7.15, Folder 10)
      Created by: Seavision Productions. Executive Producer and Director: Joseph Thompson. The making of Quetzalcoatlus Northropi by Paul MacCready funded by Johnson and Johnson (Sam Johnson) and NASM for IMAX On the Wing. Features background on PBM's Gossamer Albatross and Gossamer Condor.
    - Stone-Halinan. Paul MacCready, Ph.D. 1988. Various clips, MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_11; VHS. Color. 5 min. 25 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 11)
      Short clips from Gossamer Albatross film, Gossamer Condor film, Gossamer Penguin, Solar Challenger, footage of QN from unknown show.
    - Sunraycer, 1988; MacCreadyPB_07_03_015_12; VHS. Color. 29 min. 34 sec. (Box 7.15, Folder 12)
      Created by Desert Sky Productions for GM/Hughes. Overview of the Sunraycer project, specifically focusing on GM's role. Paul MacCready is featured as well as Howard Wilson (GM), Alec Brooks, Dr. Chester Kyle, Terry Satchell, Molly Brennan, John Harvey, Robert Stempel (GM) et al.
    - Innovative Technology: Where the Future Begins. MLS Spring Lecture Series. Eastern Michigan University, 1988 May; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_01; VHS. Color. 1 hour. (Box 7.16, Folder 1)
      Lecture. Uses footage from commercial programs
    - GM Sunraycer: The Inside Story, 1988 May; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_02; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 11 min. 36 sec. (Box 7.16, Folder 2)
      Created by Hughes Aircraft Company. Video created for internal company use of their participation in the Pentax World Solar Challenge in Australia, 1987.
    - Flying dream. 1989 Osaka exhibit, MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_03; VHS. Color. 22 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.16, Folder 3)
      Video/multimedia installation inspired by Paul MacCready and his projects. Introduction gives a brief background of MacCready.
    - Experimental Aircraft Association panel discussion, 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_04; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 30 min. (Box 7.16, Folder 4)
      Discussion on airfoils with Jack Lambie in San Diego
    - GM Sunraycer TV Highlights Worldwide, 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_05; VHS. Color. 9 min. 30 sec. (Box 7.16, Folder 5)
      Selection of newsclips from around the world covering the Sunraycer - and it's use to promote events and science education after the race.
    - Gossamer Albatross celebration at Rosemont Pavillion, 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_06; VHS. Color. 1 hour (Box 7.16, Folder 6)
      Personal video footage of celebration with speeches from various members of the GA team (Paul MacCready, et al.).
    - PM Sandia [no title], 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_07; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 30 min. (Box 7.16, Folder 7)
      Paul MacCready lecture on energy use (Doing more with less).
    - Sandia presentation, 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_08; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 20 min. (Box 7.16, Folder 8)
      Paul MacCready lecture.
    - Science Museum of Virginia Aerospace Overview, 1989; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_09; VHS. Color. 6 min. (Box 7.16, Folder 9)
      Created by Metro Communications and Science Museum of Virginia. Director: David Hagan. Asst. Director: Susan K. Wilson. Overview of the aircraft/exhibits in the Science Museum of Virginia. Includes the Solar Challenger.
    - Gossamer Albatross News Coverage, 1989 June 8; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_10; VHS. Color. 5 min. 20 sec. (Box 7.16, Folder 10)
      News clips from KNBC, KABC covering 10th anniversary of the Gossamer Albatross flight.
    - An Evening with Paul MacCready: Transparent Blinders: Catalysts for Changing Perspectives [at Caltech]; An Evening with Jonathan Miller, ca.1990; MacCreadyPB_07_03_016_11; VHS. Color. 2 hours (Box 7.16, Folder 11)
      Created by Caltech GSC/Colony Communications/Public Access. Southern California Skeptics Society.
    - CBS News Nightwatch, 1990; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_01; VHS. Color. 29 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 1)
      Created by CBS [local affiliate]. Robert Krulwich interview with Paul MacCready
    - GM Issue Update #29: Imagine the Impact, 1990; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_02; VHS. Color. 12 min. 47 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 2)
      Created by GM Employee Communications Public Relations Staff. GM company video of the Impact car.
    - Philadelphia's Earthday Weekend 1990, MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_03; VHS. Color. 5 min. 8 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 3)
      Created by Greater Media Cable, Philadelphia. Executive Producer Tom Sharrard for the Pennsylvania Environmental Council.
    - Excerpt from Johnny Carson Tonight Show - General Motors Impact joke, 1990 January 4; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_04; VHS. Color. 30 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 4)
      Clip from Tonight Show. Johnny Carson making fun of the name of the Impact.
    - 1991 National Aviation Hall of Fame Enshrinement Ceremony (Dayton), MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_05; VHS. Color. 25 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 5)
      Created by National Aviation Hall of Fame. Producer/director: Mike White. Paul MacCready is one of several award recipients.
    - Up, 1991; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_06; VHS. Color. 13 min. 53 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 6)
      Created by: Pyramid Film & Video. Producer/director Mike Hoover. Film of a man daydreaming of hang gliding in different environments.
    - Electric Auto Association meeting. Paul MacCready at Pasadena Community College, 1991 March 2; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_07; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 45 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 7)
      Created by: Electric Auto Association. Paul MacCready talks about how he became involved in making electric vehicles.
    - Chevron Research Company Leadership Series: Dr. Paul MacCready, CEO AeroVironment, Inc., 1991 May 16; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_08; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 22 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 8)
      Created by Chevron. Paul MacCready lecture on energy usage and how to create vehicles using cleaner sources of energy. He discusses the importance of aerodynamics and his major projects Gossamer Condor, Gossamer Albatross.
    - Go Farther with Charger Electric Bicycles, ca. 1992 - 1995?; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_09; VHS. Color. 5 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 9)
      Charger Electric Bicycles (GT Bicycles, Riteway Products, AeroVironment, Inc.). Promotional video for the Charger Electric bike.
    - The Era of the Car, 1993; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_10; VHS. Color. 53 min. 40 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 10)
      Created by: Vetenskapens Varld (World of Science Channel 1). Producer Lena Einhorn. Executive producer Bo. G. Erikson. Sveriges Television AB. History of the automobile focusing on environmental impact and solutions. Paul MacCready and the Impact are featured ~ 42:00. Also mentions the Sunraycer.
    - KTLA footage of rescue of Paul MacCready while hiking, 1993 November 26; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_11; VHS. Color. 20 sec. (Box 7.17, Folder 11)
      News footage of Paul MacCready being rescued after hiking alone in Strawberry Creek, Monrovia.
    - Pogo Foil, 1994; MacCreadyPB_07_03_017_12; VHS. Color. 20 min. (Box 7.17, Folder 12)
      Footage of the Pogo Foil (Parker MacCready's invention).
    - NIST 93-94 Colloquium Series - Paul B. MacCready, Aerovironment, Inc. Beyond the Gossamer Condor: Future Transportation Based on Doing More With Less, 1994 January 28; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_01; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 32 min. (Box 7.18, Folder 1)
      Paul MacCready giving talk about his experience creating the Gossamer Condor and other vehicles made by AeroVironment.
    - 1994 International Human-Powered Flight Symposium, MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_02; VHS. Color. 5 min. (Box 7.18, Folder 2)
      Children competing in human-powered helicopter project. Paul MacCready is featured in beginning.
    - Brainwaves "Lift", 1994; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_03; VHS. Color. 29 min. (Box 7.18, Folder 3)
      Created by: Kiro, Inc. Producer Karen Calvert Warner. Children's science show discussing how lift and flight works. Children visit a flight school, Boeing, Paul MacCready, and others (Raven project).
    - Ecological Design: Inventing the Future, 1994; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_04; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 4 min. (Box 7.18, Folder 4)
      Created by: The Knossus Project. Produced by Brian Danitz and Tzelovanikov. Writer Phil Cousineau. Film about the effects of design on our environment featuring environmental design pioneers. Paul MacCready starts ~ 32:06 (features footage from Gossamer Albatross film).
    - Creativity Around Us, 1995; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_05; VHS. Color. 1 hour (Box 7.18, Folder 5)
      Created by OM Association, Inc., Kendall/Hunt Publishing Company. Produced by C. Samuel Micklus, and Samuel M. Micklus. Director: Ned Eckhardt. Educational video that features a segment with Paul MacCready discussing his various projects. Discussion and Activities guide is included with the video.
    - Inventions. Series 6, 1995; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_06; VHS. Color. 9 min. 55 sec. (Box 7.18, Folder 6)
      Creator unknown. Highlight of Paul MacCready's various projects (Gossamer Condor, Gossamer Albatross, Pathfinder, Sunraycer, Solar Challenger). Includes interviews with MacCready.
    - Innovation in Spite of Education and Organization: Dr. Paul MacCready, 1995 February 16; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_07; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 18 min. (Box 7.18, Folder 7)
      Paul MacCready lecture given at GM Research & Development Center on creativity and innovation. He also talks about teaching people how to think.
    - Engineering Lecture Series "Benefiting From Change" Paul B. MacCready, AeroVironment, Inc., 1995 March 23; MacCreadyPB_07_03_018_08; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 24 min. 45 sec. (Box 7.18, Folder 8)
      Created by Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory. Paul MacCready discusses innovation despite organization. He emphasizes the importance of daydreaming, and making something out of diversity.
    - 1996 Chrysler Design Awards - Award Winners Video Module, MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_01; VHS. Color. 15 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 1)
      Designers talking about their craft. Paul MacCready is not in this.
    - Scientific American Frontiers: "Flying High", 1996 January 17; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_02; MOV. Color (Box 7.19, Folder 2)
      Created by Scientific American, Connecticut Public Television and Radio, PBS. Piece on the Pathfinder hosted by Alan Alda. Features Paul MacCready and members of AeroVironment
    - Edison Day 1996: Unleashing Creativity, Dr. Paul MacCready, 1996 February 9; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_03; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 30 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 3)
      Lecture at University of Wisconsin, Madison. Features slides and clips from various films about MacCready's projects.
    - Understanding Flight, 1996 November 24; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_04; VHS. Color. 50 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 4)
      Created by The Discovery Channel, The Cronkite Ward Co. Produced by Pamela Caragol. Exec prod. Jonathan Ward. Program discusses how flight works from birds to fighter jets. Includes Gossamer Condor, Pathfinder.
    - IMAX: On the Wing, 1997; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_05; VHS. Color. 33 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 5)
      Created by SC Johnson Wax, NASM Smithsonian. Francis Thompson, Inc, Production. Produced and directed by Bayley Silleck and Francis Thompson. Written by Bayley Silleck. Filmed for Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum. Brief history on the evolution of flight from insects to modern day planes. Features the Quetzalcoatl Northropi by MacCready and his team (near beginning and near end of film).
    - Paul MacCready talks, 1997; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_06; VHS. Color. 15 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 6)
      Paul MacCready speaking directly to the camera interspersed with clips of his projects (some from commercial programs). There are two takes of him giving the same speech.
    - Sunrayce 97, 1997; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_07; VHS. Color. 9 min. 50 sec. (Box 7.19, Folder 7)
      Created by Media Solutions. Race of solar powered vehicles created by students from various colleges across the US. Sponsored by EDS, GM and the US Dept of Energy. Finished press piece on the Sunrayce plus additional raw footage and sound bites.
    - Paul MacCready, Ph.D. (Honda Lecture), 1997 February 7; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_08; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 25 min. 45 sec. (Box 7.19, Folder 8)
      Created by Honda. Lecture given to Honda employees on creativity and PBM's experiences.
    - 1998 ASME Honors Assembly, MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_09; VHS. Color. 38 min. 2 sec. (Box 7.19, Folder 9)
      Created by American Society of Mechanical Engineers. Profiles of award winners. Paul MacCready is the winner of the Ralph Coates Roe award (2nd in program).
    - Gardner Lecture: Human Powered Flight tapes 1 & 2, 1998 April 27; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_10; VHS. Color. 1 hour, 30 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 10)
      Created by MIT. Lecture with Paul MacCready and John Langford. Features slides and clips from various films about MacCready's projects.
    - Microplane stereo system demo, Buzz Lightyear sequence, 1998 September 12; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_11; VHS. Color. 15 min. (Box 7.19, Folder 11)
      Paul and Tyler MacCready testing microplane stereo system.
    - Paul B. MacCready: Unleashing Creativity While Still Getting the Job Done. Keynote from OOPSLA 98. The 13th Annual ACM Sigplan Conference on Object Oriented Programming Systems, Languages, and Applications (Vancouver, BC), 1998 October 20 - 22; MacCreadyPB_07_03_019_12; VHS. Color. 1 hour (Box 7.19, Folder 12)